[
    {
        "question": "Who retired as the Chief Justice of India on November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Justice N.V. Ramana",
            "Justice Uday Umesh Lalit",
            "Justice D.Y. Chandrachud",
            "Justice T.S. Thakur"
        ],
        "answer": "Justice D.Y. Chandrachud",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company was ranked as the world\u2019s most sustainable aluminium company by S&P Global in 2024?",
        "options": [
            "NALCO",
            "Hindalco",
            "Vedanta Aluminium",
            "Aditya Birla Group"
        ],
        "answer": "Hindalco",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the Supreme Court\u2019s historic ruling on November 8, 2024, regarding AMU's minority status?",
        "options": [
            "The Supreme Court upheld the 1967 ruling",
            "The Supreme Court declared AMU a central university",
            "The Supreme Court overturned the 1967 ruling, revising AMU's minority institution status.",
            "The Supreme Court granted AMU full autonomy"
        ],
        "answer": "The Supreme Court overturned the 1967 ruling, revising AMU's minority institution status",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What event was celebrated from November 12-15, 2024, to honor Birsa Munda's legacy?",
        "options": [
            "Janjatiya Gaurav Divas",
            "The 5th National EMRS Fest",
            "Adivasi Mahotsav",
            "Tribal Youth Festival"
        ],
        "answer": "The 5th National EMRS Fest",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the 55th International Film Festival of India (IFFI) begin in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Delhi",
            "Goa",
            "Kolkata"
        ],
        "answer": "Goa",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Which force approved its first all-women battalion in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "BSF",
            "CRPF",
            "CISF",
            "ITBP"
        ],
        "answer": "CISF (Central Industrial Security Force)",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will the 18th Pravasi Bharatiya Divas Convention take place in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "New Delhi",
            "Mumbai",
            "Bhubaneswar",
            "Kolkata"
        ],
        "answer": "Bhubaneswar",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the Supreme Court\u2019s decision regarding illegal property demolitions on November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "The SC upheld the demolitions",
            "The SC ordered immediate demolitions",
            "The SC issued guidelines against demolitions based on mere accusations, emphasizing rights under Article 21.",
            "The SC ruled in favor of the government"
        ],
        "answer": "The SC issued guidelines against demolitions based on mere accusations, emphasizing rights under Article 21",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Canadian province reported the first human case of H5 bird flu in 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Ontario",
            "Quebec",
            "British Columbia",
            "Alberta"
        ],
        "answer": "British Columbia",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was re-elected as the World Sailing President in 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Kim Andersen",
            "Carlo Croce",
            "Paul Henderson",
            "Li Quanhai"
        ],
        "answer": "Li Quanhai",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What program did Canada end, affecting students from India and 13 other countries?",
        "options": [
            "The Express Entry program",
            "The Provincial Nominee Program (PNP)",
            "The Student Direct Stream (SDS) program",
            "The Post-Graduation Work Permit Program"
        ],
        "answer": "The Student Direct Stream (SDS) program",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is set to become the new Prime Minister of Mauritius following the November 2024 elections?",
        "options": [
            "Pravind Jugnauth",
            "Navin Ramgoolam",
            "Paul B\u00e9renger",
            "Xavier-Luc Duval"
        ],
        "answer": "Dr. Navin Ramgoolam",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What patent did Tokyo\u2019s Scarecrow Inc. receive in 2024 for canine treatment?",
        "options": [
            "A patent for a new vaccine",
            "A patent for a new surgical procedure",
            "A patent for Pinfenon (S)(R), a cardiac disorder treatment for dogs",
            "A patent for a new diagnostic tool"
        ],
        "answer": "A patent for Pinfenon (S)(R), a cardiac disorder treatment for dogs",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What cultural festival, celebrated in Uttarakhand, started on November 12, 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Kumbh Mela",
            "Ganga Dussehra",
            "Igas Bagwal",
            "Maha Shivaratri"
        ],
        "answer": "Igas Bagwal",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Which states launched double-decker electric buses in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Delhi, Haryana, Punjab",
            "Gujarat, Rajasthan, Madhya Pradesh",
            "Uttar Pradesh, Maharashtra, and Karnataka",
            "West Bengal, Odisha, Jharkhand"
        ],
        "answer": "Uttar Pradesh, Maharashtra, and Karnataka",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What new bike taxi service did Delhi Metro launch in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "A male-driven bike taxi service",
            "A women-driven bike taxi service",
            "An e-rickshaw service",
            "A carpooling service"
        ],
        "answer": "A women-driven bike taxi service",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Which project received a \u20b913,500 crore loan from the World Bank and ADB for development in Andhra Pradesh?",
        "options": [
            "The Polavaram Project",
            "The Amaravati Project",
            "The Visakhapatnam-Chennai Industrial Corridor",
            "The Rayalaseema Drought Mitigation Project"
        ],
        "answer": "The Amaravati Project",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the Delhi Mayor Polls in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "BJP's Ramvir Singh Bidhuri",
            "INC's Arvinder Singh Lovely",
            "AAP's Mahesh Kumar Khichi",
            "Independent candidate"
        ],
        "answer": "AAP's Mahesh Kumar Khichi",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the name of the event inaugurated by CM Pushkar Singh Dhami in Uttarakhand on November 15, 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Kumbh Mela",
            "Char Dham Yatra",
            "Jauljibi Mela 2024",
            "Ganga Mahotsav"
        ],
        "answer": "Jauljibi Mela 2024",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was appointed as the new Chief Justice of India in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Justice D.Y. Chandrachud",
            "Justice Sanjiv Khanna",
            "Justice B.R. Gavai",
            "Justice Surya Kant"
        ],
        "answer": "Justice Sanjiv Khanna",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was appointed as the Brand Ambassador for Thailand\u2019s tourism in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Shah Rukh Khan",
            "Salman Khan",
            "Sonu Sood",
            "Akshay Kumar"
        ],
        "answer": "Sonu Sood",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who became the Managing Director of NEHHDC in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "PVSLN Murthy",
            "Rajiv Kumar",
            "Mara Kocho",
            "K Moses Chalai"
        ],
        "answer": "Mara Kocho",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was appointed Chairman of Indian Oil Corporation in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Shrikant Madhav Vaidya",
            "S. M. Vaidya",
            "Arvind Kumar Singh",
            "Arvindar Singh Sahney"
        ],
        "answer": "Arvindar Singh Sahney",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was appointed as the CEO of the Professional Golf Tour of India (PGTI) starting January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Uttam Singh Mundy",
            "Kushal Singh",
            "Amandeep Johl",
            "Gaganjeet Bhullar"
        ],
        "answer": "Amandeep Johl",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was named Education Leader of the Year at the Education World India School Rankings 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Dr. Shyama Chona",
            "Priya John",
            "Kunal Dalal",
            "Aditya Natraj"
        ],
        "answer": "Kunal Dalal",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Which veteran filmmaker received the Satyajit Ray Lifetime Achievement Award at IFFI 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Pedro Almod\u00f3var",
            "Christopher Nolan",
            "Phillip Noyce",
            "Werner Herzog"
        ],
        "answer": "Phillip Noyce",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the Booker Prize in 2024 for the novel \"Orbital\"?",
        "options": [
            "Paul Lynch",
            "Chetna Maroo",
            "Sarah Bernstein",
            "Samantha Harvey"
        ],
        "answer": "Samantha Harvey",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airport won the 'Airport Excellence Awards' for digital innovations in 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Kempegowda International Airport Bengaluru",
            "Indira Gandhi International Airport Delhi",
            "Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj International Airport Mumbai",
            "Hyderabad Airport"
        ],
        "answer": "Hyderabad Airport",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the Men\u2019s Player and Goalkeeper of the Year awards at the FIH Hockey Star Awards 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Manpreet Singh (Men\u2019s Player), PR Sreejesh (Goalkeeper)",
            "Harmanpreet Singh (Men\u2019s Player), PR Sreejesh (Goalkeeper)",
            "Pardeep Singh (Men\u2019s Player), Krishan Pathak (Goalkeeper)",
            " \u092e\u0928\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0940\u0924 \u0938\u093f\u0902\u0939 (Men\u2019s Player), \u0915\u0943\u0937\u094d\u0923 \u092a\u093e\u0920\u0915 (Goalkeeper)"
        ],
        "answer": "Harmanpreet Singh (Men\u2019s Player), PR Sreejesh (Goalkeeper)",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the ICC Players of the Month award for October 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Deepti Sharma (India) and Babar Azam (Pakistan)",
            "Amelia Kerr (New Zealand) and Noman Ali (Pakistan)",
            "Hayley Matthews (West Indies) and Shakib Al Hasan (Bangladesh)",
            "Laura Wolvaardt (South Africa) and Mitchell Marsh (Australia)"
        ],
        "answer": "Amelia Kerr (New Zealand) and Noman Ali (Pakistan)",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What is celebrated on November 14 in India?",
        "options": [
            "Republic Day",
            "Independence Day",
            "Children\u2019s Day",
            "Gandhi Jayanti"
        ],
        "answer": "Children\u2019s Day",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "What date marks National Education Day in India?",
        "options": [
            "September 5",
            "November 11",
            "January 26",
            "August 15"
        ],
        "answer": "November 11",
        "source": "\"\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the 7th Annual India-Sri Lanka Coast Guard Meet held in November 2024?",
        "options": [
            "New Delhi",
            "Chennai",
            "Colombo",
            "Kochi"
        ],
        "answer": "Colombo",
        "source": "\"\""
    }
]